Shahabedin Yousefi (443) 430-4841

shahabyou@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shahabedin-yousefi-85629a88/

EDUCATION

Shahid Beheshti University:

Masters of Science in Information Technology Management Tehran Azad University:

Bachelor of Science in Computer Hardware Engineering

CAREER PROFILE

Extensive experience in software engineering, with a focus in design and developed e-banking and e-payment back-end application and core transaction processing system. In over 10 years utilizing various technologies to build scale complex systems long-term maintainability, performance, and reliability. Having strong background in computer science, problem solving and mathematics.

TECHNICAL HIGHLIGHTS

- Hands on: Core Java and JEE, Java 8, Spring, Restful API, Servlet, Hibernate, RabbitMQ, JUnit, TestNG, Mockito
- Databases: Oracle and Cassandra, berkeley db, ehcash
- Having experience and familiar with: JSON, XML, JMS, JSP, EJB, JPA, JBDC, Socket Programming, multi-threading and concurrency, SQL, PLSQL, XML, Java Script, HTML, CSS, C#
- C and C++, WinApi and posix
- Intellij idea, Eclipse STS, Visual Studio, Git, Maven, Visual Paradigm, Jenkins, Postman, Splunk, TeamCity, Hubbel, Allure
- Card Payment, Mobile Payment, Internet Payment, Contactless
 Payment, Issuing & Acquiring, Key Management, Prepaid, transaction
 processing, payment solutions, payment processing
- EMV, PCI-DSS, NFC, USSD, Top-up, HSM, cryptography
- Credit & Debit card, Smart Cards, e-purse and wallets
- ISO 8583, APACS
- Loyalty, Fraud, e-Voucher, Merchant Management

EXPERIENCES

Apple 2017 -

Present

Senior Software Engineer

Work at Apple as backend software engineer contractor via TCS, Utilising java8, Spring, Restful API, Servlet, JDBC, RabbitMQ, JUnit, TestNG, Mockito, JSON, XML, Oracle and Cassandra.

Fanava Card 2017

Jun 2014 - April

Senior Software Engineer Team Lead

- Design and develop Mobile Payment Gateway base on Restful API, Spring, Hibernate, multi-threading and concurrency. This system exposes payment functionality like purchase, refund, reversal and bill payment for mobile applications (IOS, Android and Win-phone).
- Develop Iso8583 enhancement on the Acquiring EMV Payment Switch and POS Channel Manager utilised Core Java, Multi-Threading, Cassandra, Oracle, Ehcash, Hibernate

PNA Sep

2011 - Jun 2014

Senior Software Engineer

- Real time Settlement System (Core Java, Hibernate, SOAP, Spring)
- Using JPos to able the current payment POS Iso8583 Channel accept discount map base in merchant attributes.

Sepehrnet Sep 2009 - Sep 2011

Senior Software Developer

- Designed and Developed a software to migrate data from a legacy core banking system (Account Base System) to a new core banking system (Client Base System)
- Develop ISO8583 financial gateway to transfer transaction between Card Management System and Core Banking Middleware using JPOS.

Software Developer

- Designed and developed Ingenico NCC (Network Communication Control) & NMS (Network Management System) (C++, POSIX, Multi-Threading, Socket Programming)
- Designed and Developed EMV base payment software for Ingenico and Sagem EFT-POS terminals (C and C++)
- Designed and developed an APACS70 standard protocol on Ingenico EFTPOS to communicate to JWARE payment switch (C and C++)
- Developed Black-List of the POS-side components of Smart Cards responsible for receiving the list of block credit cards on Ingenico POS terminals; also designed a special compound-merging and updating algorithm to execute this process (Java and C)
- Designed and Developed POS2PC as an interface between POS and bank applications (C POS side and C#.net Windows-side)

CERTIFICATIONS

- EMV Fundamental, Technical & Executive, Cardtek
- Payment Tokenization & Fraud Detection, Cardtek
- PCI DSS & PA DSS, Cardtek
- PCI DSS & PA DSS, NTT Security Limited EMV & UTA, Ingenico Group
- IngeDev, Unicapt 32 & Telium, Ingenico Group

Publications

Intention to Purchase Behavior on Social E-commerce Websites Across Cultures, by Dr. Ali Rezaeian, Dr. Sajjad Shokouhyar, Shahabedin Yousefi; published by International Journal of Computers & Technology: Vol 15, No 9 (2016)